<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mehdi&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://shahdoost.nl/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mehdi&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 22:00:58 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shahdoost.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://shahdoost.nl/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahdoost.nl/about/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s me! Mehdi Shahdoost. Being a software developer, I have an obsession with technology and coding. Having worked in the software industry for almost two decades, I have encountered a diverse spectrum of technologies, with the Java ecosystem being my primary focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT VS Apache 2.0 License</title>
      <link>https://shahdoost.nl/posts/mit-vs-apache-license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 22:00:58 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahdoost.nl/posts/mit-vs-apache-license/</guid>
      <description>MIT license is a more permissive license than Apache 2.0. Basically, you can do whatever you want with MIT-licensed software, provided you add a copy of the original MIT license and copyright notice to it. Apache is stricter because it requires you to list all the modifications you make to the original software.
Key differences The Apache 2.0 license text is much more thorough and contains more legal terminology than the MIT license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timed Text Standards</title>
      <link>https://shahdoost.nl/posts/timed-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:34:58 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahdoost.nl/posts/timed-text/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the Timed Text? Timed text is the presentation of text media in synchrony with other media, such as audio and video. Src
W3C standards for Timed text WebVTT = Web Video Timed Text TTML = Timed Text Markup Language WebVTT Format File extension is vtt. This format defines a list of &amp;ldquo;cues&amp;rdquo; that have a start time, an end time, and text to display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Design Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://shahdoost.nl/posts/github-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:34:58 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahdoost.nl/posts/github-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Every Hitech company has a set of guiding principles for creating its goods, but sometimes it might be hard to find these philosophies if you don&amp;rsquo;t work for that company. Github is really different because you can be able to quickly become comfortable with the GitHub design philosophy through an API request.
curl https://api.github.com/zen
If you use the aforementioned curl command repeatedly, you will receive one philosophy. for instance:
Non-blocking is better than blocking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
